(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
3D 爆誕祭 LIVE!?
3D Birthday Celebration LIVE!?
赤井はあと
- Haachama Channel -
Akai Haato
RED HEART
Song by Akai Haato
Hi, how are you?
Are you calling up my phone?
Baby
Baby tell me what is wrong
Don't you ever let me go
Hi, I am good
I am still looking for proof
Am I good enough for you?
Don't you tell me what's my rule
This is me
Are you coming on the ride?
We're going super high
Got to be who what I like
You and me,
Are you ready for the fight?
ALRIGHT
Stronger than I ever been before
This is who I am
Nothing in the way
Today and far away You & me
We make the part of me
I give you my big RED HEART
My my big RED HEART
I'll be true to my big RED HEART
Hi over there
Thank you for coming along
On this journey of my own
Promise me you'll won't let go
Yes, this is me
I am falling but I'm strong
Cause you got me in your arms
Don't you ever let me go
I want you to come with me on the ride
This is going super high
I am falling from the sky
Got to be who you wanna be, that's right
alright
ALRIGHT
LET'S GO!
I am still a girl
Figuring out what's true or false
In this whole wide world
I'm your only girl
Tell me once more what's really going on with you
I'm looking for the right one on the road
The one that'll always take me back to you
This can be my home, will you be my home?
Stronger than I ever been before
This is who I am
Nothing in the way
Today and far away You & me
We make the part of me
I give you my big RED HEART
My my big RED HEART
I'll be true to my big RED HEART
MUSIC: KOTONOHOUSE
SONG: AKAI HAATO
ANIMATION: ATELIER UMIVURY
はあちゃまっちゃま～！
Haachama-chama~!
ワールドワイドな最強アイドル、
The world-wide strongest idol,
はあちゃまこと、赤井はあとです！
Akai Haato, also known as Haachama!
はあちゃまだよ～！
It's Haachama~!
あれ？あれ？
Huh? Huh?
おーい！みんなー！
Hey! Everyone!
はあちゃまのこと、見てるー？
Are you watching Haachama?
はあちゃまっちゃま～！
Haachama-chama~!
ということで、今日はライブだわ！
And so, today is the live concert!
ゲストもたくさん来るから、
Since lots of guests are coming,
…めちゃ噛んじゃった、ゲストもたくさん来るから、楽しみ！
...I totally stumbled, lots of guests are coming, so I'm excited!
告知もあるから、最後まで見ていってね！
There are announcements too, so watch until the end!
それでは！今日のはあちゃまクッキングは、
Well then! Today's Haachama Cooking is...
誕生日特製ケーキ、作っていくよ！
I'm making a Special Birthday Cake!
はあちゃまっちゃま～！
Haachama-chama~!
ワールドワイドな最強アイドル、はあちゃまこと赤井はあとでーす！
The world-wide strongest idol, Akai Haato, also known as Haachama!
まずはこの、新鮮なタランチュラを、野生に返しま～す！
First, I'll return this fresh tarantula to the wild~!
かなたん見てるー？
Kanatan, are you watching?
ヴォアッ！！
Vuaa!!
これで決めるぜー！
This will settle it!
なんで、どぉぉぉぉしてお前ら、ペラッペラなんだよぉぉぉぉ！？
Why, how come you guys are so paper-thin!?
はあちゃまクッキングによる放送事故（主に映像）を阻止するため、対策を練ってきやがったのか！？
Did they come up with countermeasures to prevent broadcasting accidents caused by Haachama Cooking!?
抜いてやるぜ、毒を。
I'll remove it. The poison.
あぁ、なんということでしょう。
Oh, how could this be.
麺と虫が、優雅に、そして美しく、流されております。
The noodles and the bug are being washed away elegantly and beautifully.
これが夏の神秘
This is the mystery of summer
すべてのはあちゃまに感謝
Gratitude to all Haachamas
ロマンスの不祥事 逃がさない 消してあげる
Romance scandals, I won't let them escape, I'll erase them
先生！私が大統領になったら、人の男にちょっかいかける女は島流しにします！
Teacher! If I become President, women who flirt with other people's men will be exiled!
先生！私が大統領になったら、「いや、ただの友達だよ」ってごまかすやつはヘソから電気流します！
Teacher! If I become President, people who dodge with "we're just friends" will have electricity run through their navels!
だだだ大統領になったらね、まずは君を捕まえるね
Da-da-da, if I become President, first I'll capture you
濡れたタオルで洗いざらい吐かせるね
I'll make you spill everything with a wet towel
誰ですか あの女
Who is that woman?
やだ 誰ですか そうですか
No way, who is she? I see...
ロマンスの不祥事 逃がさない 消してあげる
Romance scandals, I won't let them escape, I'll erase them
シル・ヴ・プレプレプレジデント
S'il vous plaît-plait-plait-President
先生！私が大統領になったら、「ただの仕事の付き合いだよ」って言う奴は二度と働けなくしてやります！
Teacher! If I become President, people who say "it's just a business relationship" will never be allowed to work again!
先生！いいから聞け！「あっちが強引にさ…」って言う毒男の口にはレジンを流し込んで固めてやります！
Teacher! Just listen! I'll pour resin into the mouths of toxic men who say "they were just pushy..." and harden it!
だだだ大統領になってもね、多分君は変わらないね
Da-da-da, even if I become President, you probably won't change
しらっと、とぼけて、のらりくらり、かわすのね
You'll just keep playing dumb and dodging me, won't you?
先生、どうですか？こんばんは
Teacher, how are you? Good evening
お、本気ですか？そうですか
Oh, are you serious? I see...
ほら、情熱とは不注意、微熱も消してしまいましょう
See, passion is carelessness, let's erase even that slight fever
ワンツー
One, two!
三だ三代 大統領になっちゃったらね
If I became the third president,
マジで君を捕まえちゃうね
I'd really catch you.
濡れたタオルで
With a wet towel,
洗いざらい吐かせるね
I'll make you spill everything.
うっとっとっと どこですか? 今アンタ
Uh-oh-oh, where are you now?
見つけちゃった バレちゃった (わっ!)
I found you, you're caught! (Wa!)
よそ見するにはご用心 さようなら
Watch out for looking away, goodbye.
代わりに銃声
A gunshot in its place.
シル・ヴ・プレ プレ プレジデント
S'il vous plaît, ple, president!
トップバッター わためでしたー!
The top batter was Watame!
トップバッター わためでしたー! (イェーイ!)
The top batter was Watame! (Yay!)
実はさ
Actually...
さっき 始まる前にね
Just before we started...
脇腹をね...
The side of my body...
えっ?
Eh?
あ、なんか
Ah, something...
なんか脇腹(ハラ)してきたよね?
You just "Waki-hara'd" me, didn't you?
脇腹って...
Waki-hara?
先生!
Teacher!
先生じゃねーよ!
I'm not the teacher!
何ですか?
What is it?
ワキパイハラスメント...
Wakipai (armpit-side breast) harassment...
いい...何ですかこれ?
Wow... what is this?
ちょっと、ワキパイって何ですか?
Wait, what's "wakipai"?
見せてもらってもいいですか?
Can I have a look at it?
知らないことにつけ込んで...
Taking advantage of my ignorance...
見せてもらおうとすんな!
Don't try to get a look at it!
ワキパイって何なんだろうね?
I wonder what "wakipai" is.
脇腹わかんないね...初見殺しでもしようか?
I don't know about Waki-hara... Shall we do a "first-look kill"?
えっ、急に?
Eh, so suddenly?
しようか...
Shall we?
いや、まあね、今日お誕生日配信ということでね
Well, anyway, since it's a birthday stream today...
ということでね
That's right.
おめでとうございます
Happy birthday!
ありがとう! 本当に!
Thank you! Truly!
ケーキまだかな?
Is the cake here yet?
あ、ケーキ食べたいと
Ah, so you want to eat cake.
実はね、さっきね、空気にしてきたからね
Actually, I just turned it into air.
お?
Oh?
ケーキをね、ちょっと特製...
The cake is a special...
何ケーキですか?
What kind of cake?
タランチュラケーキでございます
It's a tarantula cake.
どうぞ食べてください
Please, have some.
初めて食べるな...
I've never eaten that before...
タランチュラもね、ついに12月9日で1周年を迎えるからね
The tarantula will finally reach its 1st anniversary on Dec 9th.
ぜひぜひ
By all means.
覚えてんだね、ちゃんと
You remembered it correctly.
そう、1周年で何かしたいんだよね
Yeah, I want to do something for the 1st anniversary.
え、記念配信やるの?
Eh, are you doing a commemorative stream?
記念で何か...やってよ
Do something for the commemoration... please.
何か追加しようかな、そしたら
Maybe I'll add something then.
つのまき...つのまきはダメよ、追加して
Tsunomaki... don't add Tsunomaki.
食べるとことか?
Like the part where you eat it?
えー、もし、もし焼かれるとしたら...
Uh, if, if I were to be grilled...
焼かれるじゃないわ、どんな感じで料理されたい?
Not grilled! How would you like to be cooked?
焼かれるって言っちゃったんだよね
You totally said "grilled".
網焼きか...ちゃうちゃうちゃう!
Grilled on a net... no no no!
ちゃうちゃうちゃう!
No no no!
てなわけでね、みんなも気をつけて、はあとも
So anyway, everyone be careful, and you too Haato.
はあとも気をつけて...
Haato, be careful too...
まあこのことについては後で考えるとして、この後はね
Well, leaving that aside for now, up next...
みこちだ! やって参るということで
It's Mikochi! She's coming to join us.
最後はつのまきジャンケンをしてね、次に移りましょうか
Let's end with Tsunomaki Rock-Paper-Scissors and move on.
OK!
はい! では、いくよ! いくよ!
Yes! Here we go! Here we go!
つのまき つのまき...
Tsunomaki, Tsunomaki...
ジャンケンポン!
Rock, paper, scissors, shoot!
ぱー!
Paper!
勝ったー! 勝ったー!
I won! I won!
ハッピー! ジャムジャム! ウー! レッツゴー!
Happy! Jam Jam! Woo! Let's go!
腰に手を当て お尻フリフリ
Hands on hips, shake your booty.
みんなおいでよ ワンダーランド
Everyone come to Wonderland.
リズムに乗って One, Two, Three
Get on the rhythm, One, Two, Three.
ときめき大好き
I love the excitement.
ハッピー・ジャムジャム 最高 踊ろうよ
Happy Jam Jam, it's the best, let's dance!
いつもの笑顔で
With our usual smiles.
ハッピー・ジャムジャム パッと 飛び出そう
Happy Jam Jam, let's jump out!
ステップ踏めば パラパパパラパパ 大好き
When we step, para-papa-para-papa, I love it!
小さくなって 大きくなって
Get small, get big.
早く集まれ ワンダーランド
Hurry up and gather, Wonderland!
太陽だって 雲だって
Even the sun, even the clouds...
キラメキ早起き
Shining, early rising
ハッピー・ジャムジャム 最高 歌おうよ
Happy Jam Jam is the best! Let's sing!
楽しい メロディ
Fun melody
ハッピー・ジャムジャム ジャンプ・アップ 遊ぼうよ
Happy Jam Jam Jump up! Let's play!
みんな友達 パラパッパ パラパ
Everyone's a friend, parapappa parapa
あなたが好き
I like you
ジャンプ ジャンプ
Jump! Jump!
ハッピー・ジャムジャム 最高 踊ろうよ
Happy Jam Jam is the best! Let's dance!
いつもの 笑顔で
With your usual smile
ハッピー・ジャムジャム ジャンプ・アップ 飛び出そう
Happy Jam Jam Jump up! Let's jump out!
ステップ踏めば パラパッパ パラパ
If you take a step, parapappa parapa
あなたが好き
I like you
最高 踊ろうよ
It's the best! Let's dance!
いつもの 笑顔で
With your usual smile
ハッピー・ジャムジャム ジャンプ・アップ 飛び出そう
Happy Jam Jam Jump up! Let's jump out!
ステップ踏めば パラパッパ パラパ
If you take a step, parapappa parapa
あなたが好き
I like you
イェーイ！ みこちー！
Yay! Mikochi!
はあちゃまー！
Haachama!
はあちゃま、おめでとー！
Haachama, congratulations!
何だこれ？ 何だこれ？
What's this? What's this?
私可愛いやろ？
I'm cute, aren't I?
おいおいおい、大丈夫か？
Hey, hey, hey, are you okay?
大丈夫か？
Are you okay?
みこちにゃはろー！
Mikochi, nyahallo!
ちょっとお邪魔しました
Sorry for intruding.
早いわ！ もう帰んの？
Too fast! You're leaving already?
もう帰んの？ はあともっと寝...
Leaving already? Haato is still sleep...
帰りません！
I'm not leaving!
むしろずっと一緒にいたい
I'd rather stay together forever.
初めて3Dで、多分一緒にこんな二人で踊ってませんか？
Is this maybe the first time we've danced together in 3D like this?
アホ毛やめて
Stop with the ahoge.
嬉しいけど、ありがとう
I'm happy, but thanks.
本当にね、はあちゃまお誕生日おめでとう！
Really, Haachama, happy birthday!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
あれ？ どさくさに紛れてハグしようとしてる？
Wait? Are you trying to hug me in the confusion?
あれ？ 何で？
Huh? Why?
どさくさに紛れてハグしようとしてる？
Are you trying to hug me in the confusion?
いやでもだってさ、ここに呼んでくれたってことは...
No, but, since you invited me here...
ああなるほどね
Ah, I see.
じゃあ今日だけ、バックハグ。
Then just for today, a back hug.
え？ いきなり？ いいの？
Eh? Suddenly? Is it okay?
したくないなら別いいけど
If you don't want to, that's fine too.
したいです！
I want to!
させてください！
Please let me!
みんな見てて、はあとみこのバックハグだよ！
Everyone look, it's Haato-Miko back hug!
お誕生日おめでとー！
Happy Birthday!
すごい、ものすごい熱を感じる
Wow, I feel an incredible heat.
はあちゃまの匂い...
Haachama's scent...
やめろ嗅ぐな！ 嗅ぐな！
Stop it, don't sniff me! Don't sniff!
やめろ
Stop it.
やめてください
Please stop.
さっきの風船のときさ、めちゃめちゃ個人プレーしてたから
During the balloons earlier, you were playing very selfishly.
ジャムジャムに合わせて殴ってたからね
Because you were punching in time with Jam Jam.
あれはもうめちゃめちゃ楽しかったね
That was really, really fun, wasn't it?
楽しかった
It was fun.
今降ってこれないのかな？
Can't we get them to fall now?
降って降って降って
Fall, fall, fall!
殴りてぇ、あれ殴るの楽しいんだ
I want to punch! It's fun to punch those.
ほらジャムジャム！
Look, Jam Jam!
当たってる当たってる、みこに当たってる
It's hitting, it's hitting, it's hitting Miko.
みこに当たってる？ 嘘！
It's hitting Miko? No way!
風船殴ってるだけじゃん！
I'm just punching balloons!
割れるよほら、ジャムジャム！
They'll pop, look, Jam Jam!
この子めちゃめちゃ元気なんだけど！
This girl is so energetic!
ジャムジャム！ ほらよ！
Jam Jam! Take that!
めっちゃパーンってなってる
They're popping like crazy.
お誕生日のことにお願いするのは申し訳ないんだけど
I feel bad asking on your birthday, but...
写真を...
A photo...
写真を撮らせていただければなと
I'd like to take a photo with you.
いいわよ
That's fine.
いいの！？
Really!?
写真だけでいいの？
Is just a photo okay?
撮りたい撮りたい、撮ろう撮ろう
I want to take one! Let's take it.
写真だけでいいんか？
Is just a photo okay for you?
写真以外にも何かオプションがあるんですか？
Are there other options besides a photo?
ちなみにわためとはチュッしたよ、裏で
By the way, I kissed Watame behind the scenes.
え？ はあちゃま！？
Eh? Haachama!?
何で！？ 何で！？
Why!? Why!?
わためだけ！？
Only Watame!?
ぎゅー！
Hug!
いやだ！ ぎゅー！
No way! Hug!
何で... 何でお前が...
Why... why are you...
ちょっと待って
Wait a minute.
マジですべてが吹っ飛んだんだけど
Seriously, everything just blew away.
なるほどね
I see.
あ、じゃあみこちとも
Ah, then with Miko-chi too...
みこちと乗り換える？
Wanna swap to Miko-chi?
え？乗り換える？
Eh? Swap?
みこち...
Miko-chi...
あ、乗り換える？
Ah, swap?
ちょ、待って待って、なんだなんだ？
Wait, wait a second, what's going on?
乗り換えたいと、乗り換えたい
Saying I want to swap, want to swap.
結婚する？
Shall we get married?
え？ははは、結婚？
Eh? Haha, marriage?
なんで？なんで一方的にプロポーズ...
Why? Why a one-sided proposal...
え、でもちょっと、はあちゃまの...
Eh, but a little of Haachama's...
やっぱりあの、ほっぺに、ほっぺにちゅーぐらい...
As expected, at least a kiss on the cheek, on the cheek...
あ、いいよ
Ah, sure.
いいの？
Really?
あ、はあちゃまのほっぺちゅー
Ah, a kiss on Haachama's cheek.
え、まあ...してほしいよ
Eh, well... I want you to do it.
え、してもらってもいいですか？
Eh, can I have you do it?
ちゅ！
Smooch!
あ、やばいよ！
Ah, this is bad!
やばいよ！待てよ！待てないよ！
This is bad! Wait up! I can't wait!
え、なんかさ、会場のみんなとも撮りたいな
Eh, I kind of want to take a photo with everyone in the venue too.
ね、撮りたい！みんなに撮ってほしい
Yeah, I want to! I want everyone to take one.
カメラさんが...
The cameraman...
あ、すごい！すごい！
Ah, amazing! Amazing!
結婚しまーす！
We're getting married!
はあちみです！
It's Haachimi!
許さないぞ！離さないぞ！あぁぁー！
I won't forgive you! I won't let go! Aaaah!
結婚してー！このチャンスを逃さないぞ！
Marry me! I won't miss this chance!
あぁ、脳密に、脳密に手を繋がれている
Ah, our hands are joined so tightly, so tightly.
離さないよー！
I won't let go!
やったー！かわいいー！
Yay! So cute!
みんなありがと、今日は！
Everyone, thank you for today!
結婚しました！あ、です！
We got married! Ah, we did!
なんでだよ！
Why though?!
え、今好感度はさ、何パーセントぐらいなんですか？
Eh, what's the affection level at right now?
好感度は1パーセントぐらいかな？
The affection level is about 1%, I guess?
じゃちょっと、お疲れ様でしたー
Well then, thanks for the hard work.
勘弁してー！ねぇ！勘弁してー！
Give me a break! Hey! Give me a break!
え、じゃあ本当は何パーセント？
Eh, then what is it really?
うーん、81.0003パーセントぐらい
Hmm, about 81.0003%.
え、それってほぼ、ほぼってことじゃん！
Eh, that's almost... that means it's almost 100%!
はあちゃま、まさか照れ屋さんなのかな？
Haachama, could it be you're just shy?
うるさい！うるさい！
Shut up! Shut up!
じゃあこのまま持って帰る！持って帰る！
Then I'll just take you home like this! Taking you home!
ありがとー！どうもー！
Thank you! Goodbye!
おーい！バイバーイ！あぁぁー！
Oi! Bye-bye! Aaaah!
KING
作詞・作曲:Kanaria
Lyrics/Composition: Kanaria
幽閉　利口　逝く前に
Imprisoned, clever, before dying
幽閉　利口　昿に惨に
Imprisoned, clever, in vastness and misery
幽閉　ストップ　知ったないし
Imprisoned, stop, I didn't know
勘弁にしておいたのだ完全に
I've completely spared you
既視感まで這う　ケラのアイロニー
The irony of a mole cricket crawling to deja vu
誰もが消えちゃう　無機質なような
Everyone disappears, as if inorganic
一足先に　叫び始めた　太陽ら
The suns that started screaming a step ahead
先が見えない　パジ・ハテーショ
An invisible fuzzy hesitation
無いの　新たに　お願いひとつ
I have nothing, just one new request
愛も変わらず　おまけに warning warning
Love remains unchanged, with a warning warning to boot
無いの　新たに　お願いひとつ
I have nothing, just one new request
張り詰めた思い込め
With intense feelings poured in
Left side, right side
歯を剥き出して　パッパッパ
Baring teeth, pa-pa-pa
照れくさいね
It's embarrassing
Left side, right side
歯を剥き出して　パッパッパ
Baring teeth, pa-pa-pa
YOU ARE KING
むせ返り遊ぶ　出来立てのダーリンダーリン
Choking while playing, a freshly made darling darling
噛み合わない笑う　痛いのの消えり
Laughter that doesn't mesh, the pain fading away
無様に死ねる　苦い思いも無くなって
Dying unsightly, even the bitter thoughts are gone
La la la　忘らる　嫌い嫌いの　最低泣いてダウン
La la la forgotten, hate-hate's worst crying down
無いの　新たに　お願いひとつ
I have nothing, just one new request
愛も変わらず　ピックアップの warning warning
Love remains unchanged, a pick-up warning warning
無いの　新たに　お願いひとつ
I have nothing, just one new request
張り詰めた思い込め
With intense feelings poured in
Left side, right side
歯を剥き出して　パッパッパ
Baring teeth, pa-pa-pa
洒落臭いね
It's presumptuous
Left side, right side
歯を剥き出して　パッパッパ
Baring teeth, pa-pa-pa
YOU ARE KING
うわぁー！ジャムジャム！ジャムジャム！
Waaa! Jam Jam! Jam Jam!
はあちゃまなんか...
Haachama, you were like...
あのリハーサルの時言いましたよね？
I told you during the rehearsal, didn't I?
ハッピージャムジャムを引きずらないでくださいと
Please don't carry over the Happy Jam Jam dance.
ジャムジャム！
Jam Jam!
ずっと笑いこらえてるんだもん
I've been holding back laughter the whole time.
ね、はあちゃ...え？
Right, Haacha... eh?
YOU ARE KING...
いやいやいや！ハッピージャムジャムのダンスしたよね？
No no no! You did the Happy Jam Jam dance, didn't you?
え、してないよ！
Eh, I didn't!
いやいや！こっそりしたよね？
No no! You did it secretly, didn't you?
さっきさ、笑いこらえてたでしょ？
I saw you trying to hold back your laughter earlier.
バレた？
You caught me?
バレたじゃない、そっくり返せよ！
Don't 'caught me' me, give it back!
はあちゃま、お誕生日おめでとう！
Haachama, happy birthday!
ありがとう！生まれた！
Thank you! I was born!
生まれたねえ。
You were born, weren't you?
生まれたね、ちょっと遅いけど。
You were born, although it's a bit late.
そんなのは気にせず、今日は8月10日。
Don't worry about that, today is August 10th.
そうだよね、今日8月10日だから皆様、今日生まれました。
That's right, since it's August 10th, everyone, she was born today.
気づいた？はあちゃまクッキングで、鍋の中にかなたの手裏剣入れたんだよね。
Did you notice? In the Haachama Cooking, I put Kanata's shuriken in the pot.
ちょっと待って、何の話だろう。
Wait, wait, wait... what are you talking about?
それ、あれ、前に一緒に3Dやった時の話？
Is that about when we did the 3D stream together before?
かなたの手裏剣を入れたんです、今日。
I put Kanata's shuriken in it today.
待って怖い、何の話ですかちょっと。
Wait, that's scary. What are you talking about?
今日は料理したんです。
It was for the dish today.
あ、そうなんですね。
Oh, I see.
それかなたは、僕入ってます？
So, was I in there?
そうだよ。
Yes, you were.
おかしいですよ、なんでかなたいるの？
That's weird! Why am I in there?
ここ、天界だったんです、実は。
Actually, this place was heaven.
もう、死んでる！？
I'm already dead!?
おめでたい席で殺すんじゃないよ！
Don't kill me on such a happy occasion!
しかもかなたが殺す側っていうね。
And yet, you're the one who does the killing.
そうだよ！誕生日だから何でも許されるでしょ！
That's right! It's my birthday, so anything is forgiven!
まあしょうがないよね、今日ばっかりは手裏剣を料理に入れられてても許しましょう。
Well, I guess I have to forgive you for putting shurikens in the food today.
あの、会場のみんなと写真撮ろうよ。
Hey, let's take a photo with everyone here.
あ、撮ろう撮ろう、写真撮りたーい。
Oh, let's do it! I want to take a photo.
やっぱり3Dだからかっこいいポーズ決めたいよね。
Since it's 3D, we should strike a cool pose.
あ、いいいね。
Oh, that's good.
ふざけんなよ！さっき言ってたのと違うじゃん！
Wait a minute! This isn't what we talked about earlier!
意味分かんねえ！最後にこれやりたいって言ったじゃん！
I don't get it! You said you wanted to do this at the end!
最後にこれやりたいって言ったのははあちゃまだからね。
You were the one who said you wanted to do this at the end, Haachama.
角度が違うのよ、もっとこう。
The angle is wrong. Like this, more like this.
うわかっこいい！何この光！
Whoa, cool! Look at that light!
今の光いいよ！
That light just now was great!
黙って遊ばれてる、光で遊ばれてるよ今。
They're playing with the lights, aren't they?
何言ってんのもう。もっと他にもかっこいいやつ思い出して。
What are you talking about? Think of some other cool poses.
やっぱこれじゃない、さっきやったこれ。
How about the one we did before? This one.
かっこいい！決まりすぎ！
Cool! Perfect!
私かっこいいなあ、惚れたかな？
I'm so cool. Did you fall for me?
やめてくださいよ！
Stop it!
待って、この足を蹴ったタイミングで光がかっこいい感じになったら良くない？
Wait, wouldn't it be cool if the lights changed when I kicked my leg out?
あ、待って。じゃあせーので行くよ。
Oh, wait. Okay, let's go on three.
せーの！
Ready, go!
うわすごい！かっこいい！
Whoa! Amazing! Cool!
アイドルらしいポーズ決めよう。
Let's strike an idol-like pose.
どう？誰？
How's this? Who was that?
ふざけんな！おい、あなただよ！
Stop messing around! Hey, it was you!
誰だよ今の声。
Who was that voice just now?
誰だよお前、おかしいだろ！
Who are you? This is weird!
行動パターンが同じすぎて！
Our behavior patterns are too similar!
ちょっと、僕にいたずらしてませんか？
Hey, are you pulling a prank on me?
これ取って食料にする。
I'm taking this and making it food.
やめてください！取らないで、天使の輪っか取らないで！
Stop it! Don't take it! Don't take the angel's halo!
これを隠し味に...やめろ！隠し味って何だ！
This will be the secret ingredient... Stop it! What's a secret ingredient!
自分のこれ取れよ！
Take yours instead!
ダメだって！これははあちゃまの生命の源、脳みそと同然なんだから！
No! This is the source of Haachama's life! It's basically her brain!
まとめられるかな？はあちゃま。
Can we wrap this up, Haachama?
嫌だ！かなたんまとめて！
No way! Kanatan, you wrap it up!
なんでだよ！僕何もしてねえぞ！
Why me? I didn't do anything!
この後はエンヴィーベイビーを歌いたいと思います！
Next, we're going to sing 'Envy Baby'!
かっこいい曲だね、引き続きかっこいい曲どんどん行くぞ！
That's a cool song! Let's keep going with cool songs!
クールに決めてくからな！見てね！
We're going to be cool! Watch us!
かなたもクールに最後締めましょう。
Kanata, let's end this coolly too.
じゃあクールに、行くよ。
All right, let's do it coolly.
せーの！
Ready, go!
Hi! I want a pizza!
愛さるるより愛したる
I'd rather love than be loved
エスカレートする飽くを得る
Gain an escalating insatiability
壊されるそんなベイビー
Being broken, such a baby
ホワイト目がけて無為間に砕かれる
Heading towards white, crushed in a moment of idleness
そんな将来
Such a future
ハイに気ままにロンリーロンリー
Loneliness in the high, as I please
吐いた言葉でローニーローニー
With the words I spat out, lonely lonely
愛も変わらず後悔なんてない
Love remains unchanged, no regrets
It's amazing!
Insanity is this Love Baby
アイゾラサマ　人の目はライライヤ
Your highness, people's eyes are liar liar
嗚呼　愛したら過ぎたことまで　好きすぎる
Ah, when in love, I love even the past too much
一ツ、二ツでライライラビンギュ
With one, two, Lie Lie Loving You
そんな言葉で　そんなことして　ジャママママ
With such words, doing such things, Jam-ma-ma-ma
一度きりのラブマニア　全部泣き言重ねて
A one-time Love Mania, piling up all the complaints
ハイファイ　媚びせよライライヤ
Hi-Fi, flatter them, Liar Liar
演技真似て　会話隠して
Imitating acts, hiding conversations
満たし重ねてロンリーロンリー
Accumulating fulfillment, lonely lonely
きっと貴方はロンリーロンリー
Surely you are lonely lonely
愛も変わらず後悔何遍？
Love remains unchanged, how many regrets?
Hey, It’s amazing.
ラララ　All it is Love Baby
La la la, All it is Love Baby
アイゾラサマ　一人凍り行く手に
Your highness, on the path of freezing alone
Insanity is this Love Crazy
アイゾラサマ　人の目はライライヤ
Your highness, people's eyes are liar liar
嗚呼　愛したら過ぎたことまで　好きすぎる
Ah, when in love, I love even the past too much
一ツ、二ツでライライラビンギュ
With one, two, Lie Lie Loving You
そんな言葉で　そんなことまで　ジャママママ
With such words, even such things, Jam-ma-ma-ma
Is this Love Baby
This is Love Baby
何だいこれ！？
What is this!?
ねぇ、これ何！？
Hey, what is this!?
揃っちゃったよ何かｗ
We ended up matching somehow lol
まあ、まあいいかと思ってｗ
Well, I thought it was fine lol
これ何だい？最後のこれ何だい？
What's this? This last part, what is it?
さっきちょっと爆発かとりあえず飛んじゃおうと思ってｗ
I thought there was an explosion just now, so I just decided to jump lol
飛んでしまったｗ
I ended up jumping lol
なるほどね、なるほどね
I see, I see
青春、青春感じたわ今
Youth... I felt youth just now
青春！そう、青春っぽい写真撮りたいんですよ、みんなで
Youth! Yes, I want to take a youthful photo with everyone
そうか、何で青春...
I see... why youth...
ちなみに我々「からし」...
By the way, we are 'Karashi'...
3D初めてなので、もうちょっと何かないの？ｗ
It's our first time in 3D, so isn't there something more? lol
からしのこと、学友だと思ってるから
I think of Karashi as schoolmates
まあ似たようなもんだ学友だと思ってるからｗ
Well, it's pretty much the same, I think of us as schoolmates lol
そう、からし今日初めての3Dなんです
Yes, it's Karashi's first 3D today
そうなんです。記念すべき、やっと、やっと揃った！
Exactly. A memorable moment, finally, finally we're together!
だってさ、マネージャーさんから「からし」なんですか？ってｗ
Because, even our manager asked, "Is it 'Karashi'?" lol
そうなんだって！見てよさすがに！ｗ
That's right! Look at this, as expected! lol
はあと様とさ、久しぶりに「からし」でコラボした時、あれ「からし」って何で「からし」...ｗ
When I collabed with Haato-sama as 'Karashi' after a long time, I was like, 'Why is it 'Karashi'...' lol
待って待って、からしじゃなくてASSHUだから！ASSHUだからね！ｗ
Wait, wait, it's not Karashi, it's ASSHU! Because it's ASSHU! lol
そうちゃん、ちょっと知らない人に説明してあげて
Sui-chan, please explain it to people who don't know
ASSHUはASSHUなんです、えーと...
ASSHU is ASSHU, umm...
そうなんです。赤井はあとの「A」...
That's right. The 'A' from Akai Haato...
違うよ！赤井はあとの「K」だよ！「K」！ｗ
No! It's the 'K' from Akai Haato! 'K'! lol
えっ、誰？ASSHUどこ行った？
Eh, who? Where did ASSHU go?
赤井はあとの「か」で「K」なんだよ！ｗ
It's 'K' from Akai Haato's 'Ka'! lol
「からし」との読みの、「ら」は、不知火の「ら」
In the name 'Karashi', the 'Ra' is Shiranui's 'Ra'
「し」は、星街すいせいの「し」！で、「からし」！
The 'Shi' is Hoshimachi Suisei's 'Shi'! So, 'Karashi'!
えー難しい... ASSHUはAとSとHじゃん
Ugh, that's complicated... ASSHU is A, S, and H, right?
そっかｗ そっかじゃなくて忘れてたでしょｗ
I see lol Not 'I see', you forgot, didn't you? lol
ということで、みんなで青春の写真を撮ろう！
Anyway, let's take a youthful photo together!
イェーイ！最高！これが「からし」！
Yay! Awesome! This is 'Karashi'!
後ろからも撮りたい。会場のみんなも、お、いいじゃん！
I want to take one from behind too. Everyone in the venue too, oh, nice!
会場の... これ撮れるのかなこれ、おー！
In the venue... can we take this, oh-!
うわああ、みんな見えてるぜ！
Whoaaa, I can see everyone!
みんな、何億人いるんだこれ！？
Everyone, how many hundreds of millions of people are here!?
この中で何人が「からし」のことを知ってるんだ！ｗ
How many people here know about 'Karashi'!? lol
多分3人くらい！ｗ
Probably about three people! lol
すげえ！みんな「からし」のこと推してくれ！
Amazing! Everyone, please support 'Karashi'!
推してくれ、からしを！
Support Karashi!
これが青春の写真か...
So this is a youthful photo...
みんなと写真撮る、ちょっと座りなよｗ
Taking a photo with everyone, sit down for a bit lol
あなた達も自己主張激しすぎたｗ
You guys are being too assertive too lol
はい、みんな撮ってる？はい、自撮り、カモン！
Okay, is everyone taking it? Okay, selfie, come on!
はい、はあちゃま、はあちゃま、はあちゃま！
Yes, Haachama, Haachama, Haachama!
いいね、撮れた？さあ、みんなでさ、飛ぶやつ飛ぶ？
Nice, did you get it? Now, shall we do the jumping one?
飛ぶやつ？「きららジャンプ」する？ｗ
The jumping one? Do a 'Kirara Jump'? lol
斜めから、斜めからやろう！
Let's do it from an angle, from an angle!
漫画タイムきららの、きららみたいなやつ？
Like the Kirara from Manga Time Kirara?
あ、違う違う、あ、どっちどっち？どうした？
Ah, no no, ah, which way? What's wrong?
これ、これ！かっこいい光と共にジャンプ！
This, this! Jump together with cool lighting!
しゃっ、しゃっ、あ、なるほどね
Sha, sha, ah, I see
みんな、写真の準備してなさいよ、ちょっとｗ
Everyone, get your cameras ready lol
行くよ、せーの、ほい！
Here we go, one, two, hop!
うわああ、すごい！
Whoaaa, amazing!
これだ、これで、これ取れてる！
This is it, it's taken with this!
これが青春なんです。これ上手く撮れた人、ツイートして下さいねｗ
This is youth. Those who got a good shot, please tweet it lol
完璧です、完璧でした、素晴らしい！
It's perfect, it was perfect, wonderful!
あ、ちょっと待って、みんな忘れてる、はあとは今日誕生日だよ！
Ah, wait a minute, everyone is forgetting, today is Haato's birthday!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
誕生日だったんだ、はあちゃま。
It was your birthday, Haachama.
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
からしの生誕祭かと思った。
I thought it was Karashi's birthday celebration.
ふざけんなよ！はあちゃま生まれてんだわ。
Don't mess with me! Haachama was born.
でもなんか、からしもこれくらいの時期にできた気がしなくもない。
But somehow, I feel like Karashi was also created around this time.
ええ！？うそだー！
What!? No way!
いや、からし誕生日おめでとう。
Well, happy birthday Karashi.
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
あ、からしの誕生日だったか。
Oh, so it was Karashi's birthday.
はい、おめでとう。はあちゃまは何歳になりましたか？
Yes, congratulations. How old did Haachama turn?
はあちゃまは、えっと、マイナス3歳になりました！
Haachama turned, um, minus 3 years old!
マイナス3歳！
Minus 3 years old!
マイナス3歳おめでとう！
Minus 3 years old! Congratulations!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
どういうこと？
What does that mean?
やめて、突っ込まないで！
Stop, don't question it!
やめて、今おんなじようなこと突っ込んだから。
Stop, because you guys just questioned the same kind of thing.
ま、でもね、いいことね。はあちゃまとね、こうやって3Dでね、コラボすることもできてね。
Well, but, it's a good thing. Being able to collaborate with Haachama in 3D like this.
はあちゃま、ずっと遠方にいましたから。
Because Haachama was far away for a long time.
そうなんです。今、遠方がよくわかんなくなっててやべぇ。
That's right. Now I'm not sure where "far away" is anymore, it's bad.
そうだった、そうだった。そうなんだよね。
That's right, that's right. That's how it is.
今後はね、また3D、やっていきたいね。
From now on, I want to do more 3D stuff.
もう気軽にできるようになったから。
Because it's become easier to do.
みんなで殴り合いコラボしない？
Why don't we do a fistfight collaboration?
え？殴り合い？
Eh? Fistfight?
それここで終結させよう。
Let's end that right here.
フェードアウトさせてください！
Please fade out!
みんなー！ラストはそとはあちゃまのチューリングラブ！
Everyone! The last one is Sotto Haachama's Turing Love!
どーもー！そとはあちゃまの夏色まつりです！
Hello! I'm Natsuiro Matsuri of Sotto Haachama!
ホロライブ1期生、夏色まつりと申します！
I'm Natsuiro Matsuri, a 1st generation member of Hololive.
一緒に歌おうよ！
Let's sing together!
えー、しょうがないなぁ。
Ehh, I guess I have to.
オッケー、いくぞー！
Okay, let's go!
作詞: ナユタン星人 / ナナヲアカリ
作曲: ナユタン星人
Lyrics: Nayutalien / Nanawo Akari
Composition: Nayutalien
嗚呼、恋の定義が分かんない
Ah, I don't know the definition of love
まず好きって基準も分かんない
First of all, I don't even know the criteria for 'like'
要は、恋してる時が恋だし
In short, love is when you're in love
評価、テストは100点満点
Evaluation, the test is a perfect 100 points
愛は、計算じゃ解けない
Love can't be solved by calculation
まず普通の計算も解けない
First of all, I can't even solve normal calculations
要は、そんな状態が愛らしい
In short, that kind of state is lovely
アイノウ、エラーも合点だ
I know, even errors are acceptable
机の上に九九があって
There's a multiplication table on the desk
手を伸ばして解けるのに
And though I can reach out and solve it
勘違って、間違って、解のない
I misunderstand, make mistakes, and have no solution
この気持ちはなんだろう
What is this feeling?
検証は命題
Verification is a proposition
内情も少々は相対性にして
Even internal matters are somewhat relative
チューリンラブ
Turing Love
見つめあったって解けないメロウ
Even staring at each other, it's an unsolvable mellow
ワラビーズラブ
Wallaby's Love
今はワンツーステップで明かそうか
Shall we reveal it now with a one-two step?
言葉で生み出すクエスチョン
A question created with words
ハートでたかなるアンサー
An answer that makes the heart beat fast
測ったって不可解性
Incomprehensibility even when measured
僕らのBPM
Our BPM
チューリンラブ
Turing Love
宙に舞ったって信じないけど
Even if it dances in the air, I don't believe it
フォーリンラブ
Fallin' Love
今はABCすらパクりそうだ
Now I'm likely to plagiarize even the ABCs
何故か教えてオイラー
Tell me why, Euler
感想をきかせてフェルマー
Give me your thoughts, Fermat
予想付かぬ可能性
Unpredictable possibilities
今触れてみるさ
I'll try touching it now
証明しよう
Let's prove it
間違いのないように
So there are no mistakes
証明しよう
Let's prove it
この感情全部全部
All, all of this emotion
証明しよう
Let's prove it
正解があるならば
If there is a correct answer
証明しよう
Let's prove it
シンプルなQ.E.D.
A simple Q.E.D.
どこ、そこ、証明したい
Where, there, I want to prove it
目に見えない、無理難題を
An invisible, impossible challenge
ASAP 導き出したい
ASAP, I want to derive it
隣り付きたい、最接近で
I want to be next to you at closest approach
嗚呼、何度絡まったって
Ah, no matter how many times it gets tangled
公式使っちゃったって
Even if I used formulas
不可思議なこのアノマリーを解き明かすのが天才の必要条件です
Solving this mysterious anomaly is a necessary condition for a genius
三次元（立体）における点A、B間の距離を求めよ
Find the distance between points A and B in three-dimensional (solid) space
好きな感じだと思ってたのに
I thought it was a feeling I liked
座標も公式も見当たらないし
But I can't find the coordinates or formulas
参考資料にも載っていない
It's not listed in the reference materials either
君と見出してみせたいじゃん
Don't I want to show you by finding it together?
三次元（世界）におけるこの気持ちの求め方
How to find this feeling in the three-dimensional (world)
回るって、回るって
Spinning, spinning
弾んで、転がって
Bouncing, rolling
近くなって、遠くなって
Getting closer, getting further away
揺れるこの気持ちのハーモニー
The harmony of this swaying feeling
条件は命題
Conditions are propositions
特性も少々は相対性にして
Even characteristics are somewhat relative
チューリンラブ
Turing Love
騒ぎ出した胸痛くなるほど
My chest starts to ache as it begins to stir
照明は
The illumination is
今もカクトモス灯しているよ
Still lighting up the night now
曖昧を自覚して
Aware of the ambiguity
最大の仮説を
The greatest hypothesis
今ふたりなら自称できそう
The two of us could claim it now
チューリンラブ
Turing Love
見つめあったって君にメロウ
Even staring at each other, I'm mellow for you
ワラビーズラブ
Wallaby's Love
今はワンツーステップで明かそうか
Shall we reveal it now with a one-two step?
言葉で生み出すクエスチョン
A question created with words
ハートでたかなるアンサー
An answer that makes the heart beat fast
測ったって不可解性
Incomprehensibility even when measured
僕らのBPM
Our BPM
チューリンラブ
Turing Love
宙に舞ったって相違ないもの
Even if it dances in the air, there's no mistake
フォーリンラブ
Fallin' Love
今はxyzまでわかりそうだ
Now I'm likely to understand even xyz
確かめさせてピタゴラス
Let me confirm it, Pythagoras
確かに生きてる今を
The now that I'm definitely living
予測済み返して
Return it as predicted
今触れてみるさ
I'll try touching it now
証明しよう
Let's prove it
間違いのないように
So there are no mistakes
証明しよう
Let's prove it
この感情全部全部
All, all of this emotion
証明しよう
Let's prove it
正解があるならば
If there is a correct answer
証明しよう
Let's prove it
間違いのないように
So there are no mistakes
証明しよう
Let's prove it
この感情全部全部
All, all of this emotion
証明しよう
Let's prove it
正解があるならば
If there is a correct answer
証明しよう
Let's prove it
シンプルなQ.E.D.
A simple Q.E.D.
待って！
Wait!
何！？ ねえ、最後のポーズわかんない！
What!? Hey, I don't know the last pose!
え、何？ 最後のポーズ？
What? The last pose?
本当だよ、最後のポーズ、全然出来てなかった！
Seriously, I couldn't do the last pose at all!
え、待って、何見せようって言ったっけ？
Wait, what were we supposed to show?
え、はあちゃまも、え、何見せよう…
Even I... what were we supposed to...
え、何見せようって言ってたっけ、マジで！？
Seriously, what were we supposed to show!?
最後のポーズ、え、これ？
The last pose? This one?
もう疲れて覚えてないんですけど！
I'm so tired I don't remember!
やばい、マジでこの、やばいねこれ、フリ！
Wait, this is bad, this choreography!
皆さん、こんにちはー！
Hello everyone!
はい！ ということで！ 初めまして、星川さん！
Alright! So, nice to meet you, Hoshikawa-san!
あ、初めまして、星川様です。
Oh, nice to meet you. Hoshikawa-sama is here.
今日来てくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you for coming today!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
やめて！ 来ませ！ きまぜ！ やだやだやだ！
Stop! It's coming! No no no!
何何、急に手繋いで…
What, what? Why are we holding hands suddenly?
いや、なんかエモいなと思って。このホロライブのステージにね、星川が立ってるの、凄くない！？
Well, I thought it's quite emotional. Hoshikawa standing on this Hololive stage, isn't it amazing!?
あ、なるほどね、確かにね。
I see, you're right.
会場のみんな！
Everyone in the venue!
会場のみんな見えてる！？
Can everyone in the venue see us!?
見えてる！
We can see you!
今写真撮ろうよ！
Let's take a picture now!
あ、いいよ。
Sure.
え、なんか、ハートまでめっちゃいるんだけど！
Look, there are so many people even in the heart shapes!
すごい！
Amazing!
すげー！
Incredible!
え、なんかさ、夢の国に写真撮るみたいな写真、星川と撮りたいんだよね！
I wanted to take a picture with Hoshikawa like we're in a dreamland!
え、星川やだ。
I don't want to do it with Hoshikawa.
なんでだよ！ 撮るんだよ！ 一緒に撮るっつっただろ、コラ！
Why!? We're taking it! I said we'd take it together, damn it!
いいよいいよ、しょうがないな。
Fine, fine, I guess I have no choice.
撮ろう撮ろう、行こう行こう！
Let's take it! Come on!
え、ねえ、どうする？ まずは飛ぶやつ。星川こっちがいい。
What should we do? First, the jumping one. Hoshikawa, go over here.
なんでだよ！？
Why!?
行くよ。せーの！
Ready. Set!
え、ちょっ… 待って、ちゃんとやってよ、飛ぶの、飛ぶの！
Wait... hold on, do it properly! Jump, jump!
あ、いいよいいよ。せーの、ヘイ！
Ah, okay, okay. Ready, set, hey!
え、なんか、もっとさ、寄らない？
Wait, shouldn't we get closer?
あ、なるほどね。
I see.
なんか一緒に手繋いで、いいじゃんこれ。
Let's hold hands, this is good.
あ、いいいね！
Oh, nice!
行くよ。せーの！
Ready. Set!
え、これ、みんな撮れた？ 撮れた？ ちゃんと。
Did everyone get it? Did you get the shot? Properly.
みんな、もう死ぬ気で撮って！
Everyone, take it with everything you've got!
あとは、あとは？ 夢の国とりあえず…
What else? What else? Let's do the dreamland one...
え、なんか、これできない？ できない？ え、これ、あ、頭のこれをこうして…
Can we do this? Can't we? This one on the head like this...
あ、カチューシャ的な？ はいはいはい。
Oh, like a headband? Yes, yes.
可愛くない！？
Isn't this cute!?
可愛い！
So cute!
なんか、あざとく、プンプン、みたいな。プンプンみたいな感じだけど。
It's like being coy, like 'pun-pun'. Kind of like 'pun-pun'.
どう？ 可愛い？ 可愛い？
How is it? Cute? Cute?
いいじゃん、いいじゃん。
It's good, it's good.
待って、閉じちゃった！
Wait, I closed my eyes!
ラグだよ、ラグだよ、それは！ ラグだよ！
That's a lag! A lag! That was a lag!
あとは、なんかこうやってさ、座って、こう、黄昏れてるみたいな…
What if we sit down like this and look like we're spacing out...
あ、座るとかないっけ？
Oh, we can sit down?
こうやってさ、え、なんだろう…
Like this, what should we do...
え、なんか、女の子って感じじゃない！？ エモい！
Doesn't this look very girly!? It's emotional!
やばい、なんかちょっとエッチなんだけど… 見て！
Wait, this is a bit suggestive... look!
やめて、ちょっとこれはやばい。こういう感じのがいい、こういう感じ。
Stop, this is a bit much. Something like this is better.
あ、なるほどね。こういう感じじゃない？ やっぱりライブって。
I see. Isn't this what a live performance is all about?
確かに、確かに。
True, true.
みんな、ありがとうー！ みたいな。
Like, 'Thank you everyone!'
記念写真撮ります！ はい！
Let's take a commemorative photo! Okay!
せーの、ハート！
Ready, set, HEART!
せーの！ うわ、すごい！ すごい！ すごい！
Ready, set! Wow, amazing! Incredible! Amazing!
はあちゃまっちゃま、はあちゃまっちゃま、ふーふーほあー！
Haachama-chama! Haachama-chama! Fuu-fuu-hoa!
おい！ おい！ 逆！ 逆だよ！ マジでなんなんだよ！
Hey! Hey! It's the opposite! Seriously, what's with you!
バカにするからやった。ちょっと待って、誕生日なんだぞ！
I did it because you were making fun of me. Hey, it's my birthday!
あ、そうじゃん。ああ、じゃなくて、今忘れてたでしょ、今？
Oh, right. No, you just forgot, didn't you?
待ってさ、今何月？
Wait, what month is it now?
８月１０日です！
It's August 10th!
あ、今８月だった？ 星川１０月かと思ってた。
Oh, was it August? I thought it was October.
８月１０日だから、ちょっと誕生日祝って。プレゼントとかないの、プレゼント？
It's August 10th, so celebrate my birthday. Any presents?
星川がプレゼント。
Hoshikawa is the present.
ふざけんじゃねえ、待って！ 誕生日おめでとう！
Don't mess with me! Happy Birthday!
でもさ、確かにほら、写真星川がプレゼントかもしれないね。
But truly, maybe Hoshikawa being here is the present.
きもい！ そんな溜めて言うことじゃない！
Disgusting! Don't say it like that after a pause!
だって、だってさ、星川、覚えてる？ ３Ｄライブやろうねって言ってたじゃん。
But, but, Hoshikawa, do you remember? We said we'd do a 3D live together.
言ってただろ！ 照れてんの？
We did! Are you blushing?
覚えてない、待って、照れてるとかじゃない、覚えてない方強い。
I don't remember, wait, I'm not blushing, I just don't remember.
でもね、違うの。今日は星川初めての３Ｄライブなんだよ！
But no. Today is Hoshikawa's first 3D live!
そうなんだよ。エモいよね、エモい。
That's right. It's emotional, isn't it?
エモい？ 思ってる、本当に？
Emotional? Do you really think so?
重いよ！ テンションがエモくないからさ！
You're heavy! Your energy isn't emotional at all!
もう怖いよ。ねえ、ちょっと、このテンション無理！
It's scary now. Hey, I can't keep up with this energy!
なんでだよ！ 可愛いじゃん！
Why!? It's cute, right?
やだやだ、ねえ、可愛いじゃん。あ、いいじゃん、ガチ恋距離で。
No, no, it's cute. Oh, look, at a close distance.
タイトル、星川と二人っきり……二人っきり。
Title: Hoshikawa and the two of us... alone.
なんかさ、やめてよちょっと！ 後ろいっぱい人いる！
Wait, stop that! There are so many people behind us!
覚えてる、星川？
Do you remember, Hoshikawa?
私たち、私たち、初めて出会った時のこと…
About the time we... when we first met...
あ、ちなみに、はあちゃまは覚えてないよ！
Oh, by the way, Haachama doesn't remember!
星川も覚えてないわ！
Hoshikawa doesn't remember either!
あんま、微塵も覚えてないけど、初めて遊んだ時のことなら覚えてる。
I don't remember much at all, but I remember when we played for the first time.
あ、ホントに？
Oh, really?
焼肉食べた。
We ate Yakiniku.
嘘つき、しゃぶしゃぶだろ！
Liar! It was Shabu-shabu!
違う、違うって！嘘でしょ！？
No, no! You're kidding!
さっき話したばっかだろ！
We just talked about it earlier!
しゃぶしゃぶだよ！
It was Shabu-shabu!
しゃぶしゃぶか。
Right, it was Shabu-shabu.
しゃぶしゃぶでしたね。
Yeah, it was Shabu-shabu.
しゃぶしゃぶでさ、二人でさ、マジでなくちょっとこうさ、「何喋ればいいんだろう」みたいなさ...
During that Shabu-shabu meal, we were both like, "What should I talk about?"
思ってない、思ってない。
I wasn't thinking that!
いや、思ってた！
Yes you were!
気まずさそうじゃないの？
Didn't it seem awkward?
どうだっけ？
Or how was it?
でも麦ご飯ん時もね、無言が耐えられなくて...
But even during Mugohan, I couldn't stand the silence...
「あ、なんか喋らなきゃ！」と思ってた。
...so I thought I had to say something!
ね、気まずかったかもしれない。最初は。でも今はね、一緒に...
Yeah, it might have been awkward at first. But now...
今はね、一緒に洋服買いに行く仲だ。
Now we're close enough to go shopping for clothes together.
そうだよ、洋服。毎回同じとこしか行ってないけど。
That's true. Although we always go to the same place.
毎回同じとこしか行ってないけどさ、また違うとこ行きたいね。
We always go to the same place, but I want to go somewhere different next time.
ヤバいわ、ちょっと、もうそろ時間...！
Wait, it's almost time...!
ヤバい！いつの間にか忘れて話し込んじゃってた！
Oh no! Before I knew it, I forgot everything and just kept talking!
ヤバい！時間経ってた！どうしよう！
Oh no, time has passed! What should we do?
はい。というわけでね。
Alright. So...
はあちゃ、ホントに来てくれてありがとう！
Haato, thanks for coming today!
また呼べよ！また今度呼べよ！
Call me again! Call me again sometime!
ま、気が向いたら呼びます。
Well, I'll call you if I feel like it.
はい！ありがとう！
Yes! Thank you!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
はあちゃにお祝いは？
What about a birthday greeting for Haachama?
頑張ってね、これからも。
Keep up the good work from now on.
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
あいつカメラ映ることしか考えてねえ！早くはけろよ！ほら！
That girl only thinks about being on camera! Hurry up and leave! Go on!
ほら、ほら！ありがとうございました！
Go on, go on! Thank you very much!
はい、ここで大事なお知らせです。
Alright, here is an important announcement.
はあちゃまの3周年&誕生日記念グッズ
Haachama's 3rd anniversary and birthday commemorative goods...
ついに販売しまーす！
...are finally on sale!
パチパチパチパチパチパチパチパチ
(Applause)
全グッズ、まごわさび先輩に描いてもらいました。
All goods were drawn by Mago Wasabi-senpai.
いつもありがとう！
Thank you always!
まずはこちらの3周年Tシャツ。
First, this 3rd anniversary T-shirt.
はあちゃまの3年間の汗と涙が凝縮されております。
It's concentrated with Haachama's sweat and tears from these three years.
コンセプトは「はあちゃまっちゃまっちゃま」。
The concept is 'Haachama-chama-chama'.
はあちゃまが二人いるというところに注目してもらいたいですね。
I'd like you to notice that there are two Haachamas here.
このTシャツを着れば、あなたもお手軽にはあちゃまになれるよー。
If you wear this, you can easily become Haachama too!
はい、お次はトートバッグ。
Next up is the tote bag.
はあちゃまと赤井はあとのコラボレーショングッズですね。
A collaboration item between Haachama and Akai Haato.
いつの日かお互いを叩き潰しあったとは思えないような微笑ましさ。
It's so heartwarming, you wouldn't believe they were once trying to destroy each other.
あの日々を思い出せるようにグッズにしたいなと思って、
I wanted to make goods that remind you of those days,
トートバッグにしました。
...so I made it a tote bag.
はあちゃまと赤井はあとが出会えた記念グッズと言っても過言ではない、
It's not an exaggeration to say it's the commemorative goods of Haachama and Akai Haato's meeting.
そんなグッズになっております。
It's become a product like that.
とても思いがこもっております。
A lot of feelings are put into it.
そしてそして、誕生日グッズは足裏マウスパッド！
And then, the birthday goods: the Sole Mousepad!
意外と規制厳しくて、いろいろ試行錯誤して、
The regulations were surprisingly strict, but after much trial and error...
極限までエロスを引き出した、
...we brought out the sexiness to the limit in...
この足。
...these feet.
マウスを使いながら足裏を撫でることができると。
You can stroke the soles while using your mouse.
さらに、匂いを嗅ぐことができます。
Furthermore, you can even smell it.
匂いには個人差がありけり。
Individual results may vary for the scent.
この嫌がるはあちゃまの顔がね、もうたまらないのよ。
This disgusted face of Haachama is just irresistible.
隠されてる左足で妄想も捗るんじゃないの？
The hidden left foot will also surely spark your imagination, won't it?
ぜひぜひ、このマウスパッドで充実したネットライフを送ってもらいたいね。
Please enjoy a fulfilling internet life with this mousepad!
というわけで、豪華誕生日記念グッズはこの3点になります。
So, the gorgeous birthday commemorative goods are these three items.
これをフルセットで購入した先輩は、頭はあちゃまっちゃまになれるよーん。
Senpais who buy the full set will become Haachama-chama in the head!
その上、数量限定の直筆サイン入りポストカードがゲットできるかも。
On top of that, you might get a limited-edition hand-signed postcard.
そもそもはあちゃまってグッズ販売滅多にしないから、超絶激レアなんよ。
Since Haachama rarely sells goods, it's super rare!
だからそこの君、このタイミングを逃すなよー。
So, you over there, don't miss this opportunity!
はあちゃまのたくさん思いの込めたグッズ、
Please buy these goods that are filled with Haachama's many feelings!
ぜひぜひ買ってねー。
Please buy them!
よろしくー！
Thank you!
このあと21時から販売だよーん。
They go on sale from 9 PM after this!
みんな、今日は見に来てくれてありがとうー！
Everyone, thank you for coming to watch today!
とっても素敵な誕生日になりました。ホントにホントにありがとう！
It became a truly wonderful birthday. Thank you so, so much!
そしてついに、最後となりました。
And finally, we've come to the last part.
最後は「Infinity」を歌いたいと思います。
Lastly, I'd like to sing 'Infinity'.
この曲はいろんな思いを込めて作った曲なので、
I put many feelings into this song when I made it,
最後までぜひ聴いてってもらえると嬉しいです。
...so I'd be happy if you'd listen until the very end.
AKAI HAATO x HAACHAMA
Infinity - HAACHAMA
Infinity
作詞:Luschka 作曲:Naoden
Lyrics: Luschka / Composition: Naoden
Who am I?
What is mine?
Oh, tell me, did I ever lose my mind?
I wanna cry, but I can't find
From where all this is coming down
So I go find the little girl
To save her from the world
To tell her, "Cry no more"
A journey to the center of my heart
My heart
To find the girl who's deep inside my heart
One for two and two for one
I'm weak, but I'm at least no more alone
I gotta run toward the sun
The voice that's calling out my name
And I go find the little girl
To save her from the world
To tell her, "Cry no more"
A journey to the center of my heart
I'm here, eyes full of tears
Fighting all of the fears
Of losing you again
Dear my beloved one
My inner loneliness
Let's rewind the clock till we remember happiness
My heart
I am the girl who's deep inside my heart
We'll be together forever
Today I'm here, eyes full of tears
Fighting all of the fears
Of losing you again
Dear my beloved one
My inner loneliness
Let's rewind the clock till we remember happiness
3D 爆誕祭 LIVE!
3D Birthday Festival LIVE!